JOSEPH PAVICH

CASTRO VALLEY, CA 678.858.4785 | JOE@PAVI.CH

PROFILE & VALUE

Team Leadership: Establish and manage teams to achieve design, quality, and cost-driven goals.

Complete PLM Experience: Leadership through product launches including design industrialization with manufacturing support through service, maintenance, and end of cycle.

Product Ideation: Create innovative products that perform aesthetically and functionally with a focus on design for manufacturability.

Manufacturing Oriented Design: Develop physical and digitized properties optimized for reducing post-cutting room resources, Tier 1 throughput, and manufacturing costs.

Broad Product Design Experience: Technique, systems, and materials education by studying soft trim items from numerous high and low volume manufacturers in various industries.

Trending and Upcoming Design Experience: Research and application of trending and forward-thinking design and manufacturing concepts and techniques.

Material Application Expertise: Experience in proper material and substrate selection for maximum product performance in assembly, tactile appeal, and durability.

Mastery of Soft Trim Production Machinery: Extensive knowledge of industrial production equipment operation and maintenance.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Staff Mechanical Design Engineer, Design Studio TESLA

November 2017 – Present Fremont, CA

- Manage trim development cycle from concept to production on global programs.
- Drive engineering strategy for structural changes and closeout implementation on sub-surfaces.
- Design soft trim patterns for interior programs with emphasis on cost reduction and manufacturability enhancements.
- Provide global supplier support during launch of new products, production challenges, and design changes.
- Research advanced seating material concepts and develop materials for industrialization.
- Guide design and engineering counterparts toward a goal of product aesthetics with manufacturability.
- Fabricate concept designs in solid substrates and soft trim.

Senior Trim Engineer FUTURIS Automotive Group/ADIENT

October 2016 – November 2017 Newark, CA

- Managed design studio trim team with timely and DFM focused digital and physical deliverables.
- Consulted on design optimization to promote cost savings and quality improvements.
- Developed seating soft trim including foam molding, digitizing, patterning, and digital cutting.
- Constructed prototype and concept designs, presentations, and work/cost studies.
- Provided support at regional and global production facilities in regards to quality control, process improvements, and enforcing design/process changes.
- Designed production line layout, optimized process flow, and incorporated automations.
- Provided engineering support to OEMs concerning pattern improvement, closeouts, and material selection.

- Managed all staff and delegated projects throughout the team.
- Created online retail and wholesale infrastructure of automotive interior products and marketed through web-based, print, social, and physical media.
- Developed automated cutting room operation and organization with CNC cutting systems and pattern digitization.
- Drove product ideation with market demand forecasting.
- Collaborated with suppliers and manufacturers on design/creation of concept and show vehicles for industry exhibitions such as SEMA.
- Offered product design and development consulting services to manufacturers and designers of automotive, aviation, and lifestyle soft goods accessories.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Business Administration in Business Information Systems

Concentration in Business Systems Analysis and Design State University of West Georgia, Richards College of Business January 2002 – May 2004

Coursework in Engineering and CAD Design

Georgia Institute of Technology August 1999 – August 2001

Additional Career-Based Courses and Training

- Accumark software and digitization
- Mastertrim NX software
- Lectra Design Concepts and Marker Maker
- LEAN production and TPS (Toyota Production Systems) equivalency training